So, online assessment were same,
different, or how was the interview?
[music]
So, online assessment was same for
everyone. And I guess from this year
only Infosys changed this pattern. So,
in the online assessment, there were no
aptitude or reasoning questions. There
were only pure coding DSA questions. So,
that all profile that you are mentioning
21 LPA, the highest one was 21 LPA. You
could have also applied for 21 LPA role.
You can't decide your role.
>> [music]
>> The roles will be decided by the company
according to your score in the online
assessment that you did. Could you share
the question that has been asked to you
by the interviewer? And how long it
went? So, good thing about the
interviews in Infosys is there was only
a single round.
Like there were no three to four rounds
of interviews. There was only a single
round. And my interview specifically
lasted for, say, [music] 20-25 minutes.
So, hi Shrut, welcome back
to another video. So, in our previous
video, we have already discussed a lot
on your TCS Prime experience. [music]
So, those who are new to this channel
and haven't watched that video, so Shrut
Jain has cracked two companies. One is
TCS Prime and another is Infosys
Specialist Programmer. So, you could
check out the previous video of TCS
Prime. In this, he has shared [music]
whatever the question has been asked,
what was the round he has faced, and how
he handled the interview. So, it would
be pretty great information. So, those
students who wants to crack those
companies. So, in this video, we would
be particularly talking about Infosys
Specialist Programmer role. So, Shrut,
before we deep dive into your technical
stuff, again I want you to introduce
yourself because there are many who
haven't watched your previous video. So,
I would like to know a brief about you.
Uh so, hi everyone. My name is Shrut
Jain, and I'm currently a final year
B.Tech student doing my undergrad from a
IES College in Bhopal. And over the past
1 year, I have been opportunity to work
with France based startup where I
entered there as a software engineer
intern for 9 months [music] and talking
about my offer so I have two offers
currently I have two offers in hand one
is the TCS prime role and another one is
the Infosys specialist programmer role.
So yeah that was a brief about me. So
Shrut, how did you got the opportunity
for Infosys SP [music] profile? Okay, so
this was an on campus opportunity that
came to our college with around four
roles [music]
the first one was the DSC role the
second the second one was the specialist
programmer role and the specialist
programmer had three categorization the
L1 L2 and L3. So total there were four
roles that Infosys came for came came
for in our campus.
Okay, so what was the package did they
offer? Okay, so DSC was offered around
6.25 lakhs per annum plus 75,000 joining
bonus. The L1 specialist programmer were
offered 10 lakh per annum package plus
CTC plus 1 lakh rupees joining bonus and
the L2 profile was 16 LPA and the final
L3 profile was at 21 LPA.
Oh, so that all profile that you are
mentioning 21 LPA the highest one was 21
LPA. You could have also applied for 21
LPA role.
>> Uh so all of the so the roles weren't
decided specifically before like you
can't decide your role. The roles will
be decided by the company after your
according to your score in the online
assessment that you did.
If you have higher score you can you can
be allotted L3 role.
Uh so the allocation was based on the
score on the UI.
Actually I'm a bit confused like how
they could allocate L3 role because when
I was in company so L3 was the role that
the used to provide to person who has
much higher experience. [music]
So, is it uh the role that is being
provided to fresher itself? 21 LPA
starting package. Yeah, it is. I'm
pretty confused. [music]
It's so good.
>> It is like uh do you know any student or
uh nearby that who has got this much
package?
No one. No one.
At least people interviewed for that but
no one was selected.
>> Okay, they have interviewed for that
role as well. Okay.
>> Okay.
Did you find anything bit difficult or
different because they are offering nine
L 9.5 LPA for specialist programmer and
for L3 role obviously you are as you
have mentioned 21 LPA. That's a huge
difference. Uh so, online assessment
were same, different or how was the
interview? So, online assessment was
same for everyone and I guess from this
year only Infosys changed this pattern.
So, in the online assessment there were
no aptitude or reasoning questions.
There were only pure coding DSA
questions. And there were four questions
and everyone had the same way. So,
everyone had the same questions. There
were four questions. The first one was
easy. Uh the second one was medium and
the third one was hard and the final
fourth one was complex. So, there were
four questions.
And the allocation of roles were decided
on that on these questions. So, let's
say for example you solved only one
question.
>> [music]
>> So, then you will be assigned DSC role.
You will be you will be interviewed for
DSC role. If you solved two or 2.5
questions, you will be interviewed for
L2 role. Uh sorry, L1 role. And if you
saw if you somehow solved all the three
questions, the first three questions,
then you you can get L2 or L3
interviews.
Uh so, shows from your experience, could
you recall how much questions you have
solved within your OA round?
>> [music]
>> Yeah. So, I managed to solve the first
two questions completely. All the test
cases passed. And for the third
third question, it was partially solved.
Only nine out of 12 test cases passed
successfully. So, it was a partial
submission.
And fourth question was
very complex. I
>> [music]
>> I couldn't even understand it there
only. So, there is no point for me
remembering anything now.
Yeah. Okay. So, could you recall the
topics they have covered in easy,
medium, hard, or complex part?
>> So, the first question that was the easy
question,
it was a stack simulation problem. Like
>> [music]
>> straightforward the instructions were
given and you just need to simulate it
using a stack. So, it was quite
straightforward question. And the second
question was
was a variation of the classic
lead code question which is count
inversions.
All right. And the only variation was in
counting the inversions on lead code it
deals with numbers.
>> [music]
>> And here they have given alphabets. So,
that was the only difference. Rest
everything was same. And the optimal
approach was to solve it using merge
sort.
So, I remembered it there and I solved
it. And the third question was a was a
DP problem.
And
it was kind of a 2D grid
was quite complex problem.
Okay. Okay. No problem.
So, how did you find your OA as if you
can compare your OA with the TCS Prime
round because they have also offered you
the same 9.5. So, [music] if you could
compare both the OA, so which one you
found more difficult? So, the Infosys
one was quite difficult. Like TCS was
pretty easy. And
most [music] of like most of my most of
the ones who has given in the college
cleared that OA round and everyone was
sitting at the interview. But Infosys OA
was quite hard to you know
crack.
Only around I guess how much
50 or 60 people were selected for the
interviews
from a lot of 2000 to 3000 3000
students. So yeah, it was [music] quite
difficult.
Oh.
Yeah, that was quite a low number. So I
know that Infosys set their online
assessment very hard, but as you have
also mentioned they were offering for 21
LP. That was also huge.
Yes.
So moving on to the next, so when you
came to know that finally you cracked
your Infosys specialist programmer
online assessment and you were [music]
made it to that round. So how you
prepared for your interview and how was
that round for you?
Okay, so
I don't know how why Infosys did this,
[music] but the day the OA was done,
like I still remember it was some gate
[music] for something something.
The day that the OA we have we have
given, the same day they gave the result
at 12:00 12:00 in the midnight. Right?
And the next day they scheduled the
interview next day.
So there was
>> Oh, they haven't given you time for the
prepare.
>> no time, no time. Since since this was
an offline interview, so the team had
come from far away and they need to wrap
it up within two to three days. That's
why there was no time given.
So there was actually no time for
preparing for the interview. Still
I still remember me and my friends
prepared
>> [music]
>> till late in the night
and then got up and went to the
interview. That was quite quite quite
hectic.
But still we we couldn't revise
everything. We couldn't revisit
anything.
So yeah, I just
I just
scanned my resume and
I prepared whatever that was written in
in my resume and I also prepared core
subject. I revised core subjects like
operating system
>> [music]
>> and DBMS
and yeah, that was it.
Okay. Okay, so Infosys visited your
campus or you have gone to some center
to give your OA round? No, no, Infosys
visited the campus.
Okay, okay, great.
So coming back to your interview, so
could you share the question that has
been asked to you by the interviewer and
how long it went? Okay. So good thing
about the interviews and Infosys is
there was only a single round.
Like there were no three to four rounds
of interview. There was only a single
round. And my interview specifically
lasted for the same 20 25 minutes.
Right? And the questions asked were
basic questions were asked. Like the
first question that the interviewer gave
me was to implement quick sort
algorithm,
to write the pseudo code of quick sort
algorithm and explain it. And the second
question was
implementing Dijkstra's algorithm of
graphs.
>> [music]
>> Right? So the interviewer asked me to
write the code of Dijkstra's algorithm
and explain and asked me questions how
it works. And then there were
theoretical questions around data
structures like for example,
what is memoization and how it works,
how it solved the problem of recursion,
what is the difference between
memoization and tabulation,
what are the different graph traversal
methods,
what are BFS and DFS, what is the
difference in both of them and yeah,
there were theoretical questions only.
And after that the interviewer asked me
SQL queries. So those were basic SQL
queries like to implement a select query
using where clause or to implement
joins. So that were it. Then the
interviewer came to my resume. So he
started asking questions around Spring
Boot
>> [music]
>> like what are beans in Spring Boot, what
what is the bean life cycle,
how you
how how implement a repository in a
Spring Boot application,
what are repositories in Spring Boot
application, what are annotation and
what are the different kinds of
annotations in Spring Boot.
Uh so, this was about Spring and Spring
Boot. And then after that,
yeah, the complete interview was around
this only. [music] And
it lasted for only 20 minutes and it was
completed pretty early as compared to my
other
other college mates. So, the interviews
were lasting for 1 1 and 1/2 hour.
And mine lasted for only 20 minutes. So,
>> [music]
>> I was pretty sure that I'm not going to
get selected.
Uh but somehow I I got selected. And the
interview also the interviewer at last
also said that, you know,
uh he is
>> [music]
>> quite, you know, happy with the
technical knowledge of mine and that's
why he ended the interview.
So, that's it. Uh so, within the coding
round, uh so,
have you followed brute force approach
or optimized approach? Because I know
that first of all, whenever the question
that interview asked to you to related
coding, we have to follow brute force
and then we need to optimize it more.
So, how was your experience with the
interviewers? Okay, so, for the first
question, which was to, you know,
implement quick sort algorithm, it was
straightforward. I just straightforward
told them that this is how we are going
to do it.
Uh directly the optimal approach. And
for Dijkstra also, there was a single
approach but using different data data
structures. So, I told them that we can
do it using priority queue. We can also
do it using sets. And we can also do it
using a simple queue in certain cases.
Uh there are there are certain cases
that we can also implement that using a
simple queue.
>> [music]
>> And I also discussed the trade-offs
between trade-off between them between
each data structure. What are the pros
and cons of using each data structure?
>> [music]
>> Uh so, yeah, that was about the this
question part.
So, Ashutosh, I just wanted to know
about your preparation strategy, that
what preparation strategy you followed
in order to crack Infosys specialist
programmer role if one who's preparing
for this role can follow the strategy
and would be able to get through. Let's
suppose there are many students who used
to message me that yes, my interview has
scheduled
there would be Infosys specialist
programmer
online assessment round within 3 months,
within 6 months. How to prepare for it?
Let's suppose one has a target of 3 to 4
months or 6 months. [music]
Is it feasible or one can target this
particular profile within that short
time?
Okay, so yeah, What do you think? Yeah,
in 3 to 6 months is quite feasible if
you have some knowledge of DSA and you
have done some problems. Like if you are
completely new and you are just starting
off with DSA then it's quite difficult.
But the strategy would be for OA the
strategy for OA
would be to start giving Leadcode
contests. Like don't rely completely on
some sheet or or some predefined
standard problems.
>> [music]
>> Those problems will be helpful for you
in interviews but they won't be helpful
in OAs. So for OA you can start giving
Leadcode contests and
if you can you can also give a you can
also start giving CP contests like on
Codeforces or Codechef. So that thing
helped a lot and uh
Yeah, yeah.
That was for the OA part.
>> But but what do you think? Yeah, but I
know that Infosys has been increasing
its level day by day. I totally agree
with you that only Leadcode question
wouldn't help [music] in long way
because as their questions have been
pretty complex.
>> [music]
>> But
but there are many students who are not
giving these Leadcode contests or
Codeforces.
Many students used to do or used to
learn DSA and then they used to do
coding on Leadcode, HackerRank platform.
So don't you think that uh were they
able to crack these interviews or you
have seen your
friends as well who have been cracking
these role while doing the same?
Uh, so yeah, as you said there are some
of my friends that you know crack the
Infosys or any other way without even
giving contest or
without even giving contest or doing CP.
So uh the the strategy in such cases
would be to
you know
uh
do the standard problems very
thoroughly.
Right?
Uh
you might like
and another skill is to recognize
patterns whenever you are given a DSA
question. That that is very important.
That is very important. In OAs generally
in online assessment rounds, they won't
give you direct equal questions or
straightforward questions. There will be
a whole lot of a story. Like the like
the the question would be a one page or
two page two pages long.
So you need to recognize that pattern.
You need to make that key observation
uh that is required to solve that
problem. So that observation skills
matter a lot and how you will increase
them? By solving more and more problems.
Yes. So I think it would be pretty
helpful for those who are doing
competitive
uh programming and doing code forces
because they have already gone through
such a same problem. So it would be easy
for them. Mhm. I would agree with that.
>> So the guys who do CP is what I've
observed that they they have very great
observation skills. Right? They they
they can build that intuition very
quickly as compared to a normal lead
code guy or who who who just solves
standard problems.
>> [music]
>> That's what I I have That's what I have
observed basically.
So the main thing eventually is to build
that intuition and build those
observation skills of yours.
So it can be done using CP if you are
doing CP or it can be done using lead
code problems also. Uh no problem. So
did provide you with offer letter?
No offer letter didn't came to me.
Okay. Okay. So, you have no idea
regarding your training and all those
stuff till the date. [music]
>> Yeah, there there so Infosys sent a mail
to all the candidates that you know
they'll be on boarding everyone of them
after graduation.
Okay. Okay. So, great to know. Okay, so
that was great to know about your
Infosys specialist programmer role and
Infosys training is too good. I have
already
taken the experience of that. So, I hope
you would also enjoy that and get a
great experience there. Sure. Sure.
Yeah, so thank you so much for coming to
my channel and hopefully I have created
two videos with you and I think that in
future also when you complete your
training, you could come to my channel
and share your Infosys training
experience. Sure. Sure.
>> And we will share it with the audience.
Yeah. Yeah. Sure. Sure.
Definitely.
>> Definitely. Yeah, so it was Yeah, so it
was great to have you here and so those
who are watching this video with Shubh
we have discussed on TCS Prime and
Infosys specialist programmer role we
have already covered in this video. So,
those who haven't watched that video so
go and click on the button and just go
and check out that video. In that video
also Shubh has discussed a lot of thing
regarding TCS Prime role, all the
questions offered has been offered, his
preparation strategy as well. So, that
way it would be going to help you out in
cracking your interviews. So, thanks.
Thanks Shubh for coming to my channel.
Thank you. Thanks for watching.
>> Yeah. Thank you very much. Thanks for
having me and subscribe to girls channel
>> [music]
>> obviously.
>> [laughter and gasps]
>> Yeah, thank you so much Shubh. Thanks.